starnow.co.uk 2019-12-12

# Privacy Policy - StarNow

This privacy policy applies to all personal information collected, stored, used and transmitted by StarNow (owned and operated by StarNow Limited). StarNow’s contact information is provided at the end of this privacy policy.

For the purposes of the EU General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"), if you are based in the European Union, StarNow is both a controller and processor of your personal information.

We may amend this privacy policy at any time by posting [the amended policy on our website](https://www.starnow.co.uk/privacy-policy/) ("Website"). All amendments to the privacy policy will take effect immediately upon such posting.

StarNow's services are described in full in [StarNow’s terms of use](https://www.starnow.co.uk/terms-and-conditions/) ("Terms of Use"), as updated from time to time.

### Privacy of your information

StarNow collects personal information about you through your use of the services and the Website, including your registration details; and information relating to your use of the Website and the content you access.

If StarNow is unable to collect personal information from you, your use of StarNow’s services may suffer from reduced functionality, and certain features of the service may be disabled.

You agree that StarNow may process your personal information:

  * as necessary to provide the services to you and otherwise comply with its obligations to you under the Terms of Use. For example: 
    * all personal information that you provide to StarNow for inclusion in your personal profile will be collected and stored on the StarNow Website to enable visitors to the Website and advertisers to view your profile, and your profile will also be accessible from search engines such as Google (unless you have set your profile to Private); and
    * where you choose to apply for any role advertised through StarNow your contact details and any information entered into your personal profile will be provided to the advertiser (including any photo you have uploaded);
    * where you have placed a listing or advertisement, any information entered into the listing details will be provided to applicants
  * where it is necessary for the purposes of a legitimate interest pursued by StarNow, being for ensuring Trust and Safety of users of the service, or StarNow’s internal business purposes (including in connection with any audits, professional advice, research, testing, analytics, fraud prevention, or process and service improvements), to verify your identity, and for contacting you from time to time about your registration, account updates, and promotional information about the StarNow Service and features;
  * where necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which StarNow is subject. For example, StarNow may disclose your personal information, including your name and contact details, to the relevant authorities, parties and/or the applicable intellectual property right holders (or their representatives) where the law requires or allows us to do so.

### Your Rights

You have the right to access and correct your personal information that is held by us at any time. Requests for such access and correction requirements can be made to the contact details at the end of this privacy policy.

If you are a resident of the EU (including the United Kingdom), you also have the right to:

  * request the erasure of any or all of your personal information;
  * restrict or object to the processing of any or all of your personal information;
  * request the porting of any or all your information to another organisation;
  * withdraw any consent to processing that you have previously given in respect of any or all of your personal information (where it does not prevent StarNow from complying with its obligations to you under the Terms of Use);
  * lodge a complaint regarding our data processing activities as they relate to your personal information with the supervisory authority in your member state.

Please note that where StarNow is not, or is no longer, in a position to identify you within the information we hold (including because of any de-identification techniques we may have employed), then your rights as described above shall not apply.

StarNow will respond to any request made in respect of the above in accordance with the GDPR where you are resident of the EU (including the United Kingdom), and in all other instances in accordance with the Privacy Act 1993 (New Zealand).

StarNow will respond to any request made in respect of the above without delay, but in any case within one (1) month of a request, or two (2) months where the requests are complex or numerous (in which case, we will inform you of such delay). 

### Data Minimisation, Retention and Erasure

StarNow will only collect personal information that is necessary for the legitimate purposes and on the lawful basis described in this privacy policy, and otherwise as expressly consented to by you.

If you make a request for StarNow to delete your personal information, and we no longer have a legitimate purpose to retain your data, we will securely delete your profile and personal data. Any back-up copies of your data will be archived out and deleted within 45 days of your request being actioned.

If you wish to retain a copy of your personal information (or any part of it) please contact StarNow (using the details given at the end of this privacy policy) prior to you requesting deletion of your data.

Despite the above, StarNow may:

  1. in some cases, retain a copy of your profile and account activity in order to fulfil our Trust and Safety obligations. Data retained for Trust and Safety purposes will be archived and stored in a secure manner after your account has been closed, and will not be accessed unless required for Trust and Safety reasons.
  2. Retain personal information in an aggregated, de-identified or otherwise anonymous form, such that there is no reliable way of identifying you from the information.

### Data Security

StarNow will collect, store, use or transmit your personal information securely using technical and administrative security measures as are reasonable in the circumstances and that reduce the risk of accidental or unauthorised loss, misuse, access, disclosure or alteration.

Please note that when providing personal information to StarNow via the Website, the transmission is not completely secure and will depend on your browser and internet settings. StarNow cannot guarantee the security of data transmitted to StarNow via its Website and any such transmission is at your own risk.

### Cookies

A cookie is a piece of information that is stored on your computer’s hard drive, or on your mobile device. StarNow offers many features that are only accessible when cookies are enabled. Cookies also help us to remember your membership details and preferences.

If you visit StarNow with your browser settings adjusted to accept cookies, we understand that you want to use our products and services. However, you can disable cookies at any time.

Find out more about [cookies](https://www.starnow.co.uk/help/cookies/) and learn how to [adjust your cookie settings](https://www.aboutcookies.org/default.aspx?page=1).

### Third Party Websites

StarNow may contain links to other websites ("Third Party Websites") and either StarNow or you may post your information on such other websites (including, but not limited to, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and YouTube). If you choose to use a Third Party Website, the relevant service provider (or website, as applicable) may use and share your data in accordance with its own privacy policy and your privacy settings on that Third Party Website. You should always review the privacy policies applicable to Third Party Websites to make sure you are comfortable with the ways in which they use information you share with them. 

### Third Party Services

StarNow may also use third party providers to provide certain services to you in connection with your membership on StarNow. StarNow may disclose personally identifiable information to these third party service providers for the sole purpose of the provision of services to you or in connection with your membership of StarNow. 

A list of the categories of third party service providers StarNow uses to provide services to you in connection with your membership on StarNow is provided below:

  * web hosting services (such as Rackspace and Microsoft Azure)
  * direct marketing services (such as Mailchimp, SendGrid and Returnpath)
  * marketing and remarketing services (such as Google Adwords and Facebook)
  * analytics and reporting services (such as Google Analytics)
  * site security and monitoring services (such as Raygun)
  * payment services and billing agents (such as Worldpay, PayPal, DataCash, Spreedly, Apple, Internet Payment Services Limited)
  * mobile app services (such as Apple)
  * social Media services (such as Instagram, Facebook, Twitter)
  * collaboration and documentation services (such as Slack, Evernote, Google Docs)
  * UK advertiser and marketing services (such as Casting Days)
  * Customer Relationship Management services (Pipedrive)

StarNow will only use trusted third party service providers for the sole purpose of the provision of services to you or in connection with your membership.

In some cases, for the purposes of the GDPR, some third party services may be considered to be Data Controllers – in particular Worldpay who is a third party service that processes transactional personal data relating to credit card payments. Please view their Privacy Policy [here](https://www.worldpay.com/uk/worldpay-privacy-notice).

### Remarketing

StarNow also uses third party remarketing cookies, in particular, Google AdWords. These remarketing services may place cookies on web browsers in order to serve ads based on past visits to our website. This means you may see ads about our service across the Internet, specifically on the Google Content Network (GCN). This allows us to make special offers and market our service to those who are interested in our service, and only display ads that are relevant to you.

We respect your privacy and do not collect or store any personally identifiable information through Google AdWords or any other third party remarketing system.

If you do not wish to see ads from StarNow you can opt out in several ways:

  1. Opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting Google's Ads Settings.
  2. Opt out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.

### Spam and your email address

Your email address or Facebook account is used to identify your membership, and to sign in to the site.

After registering with StarNow you will receive regular casting call update emails, containing casting calls and auditions matching your profile. You may also receive our email newsletters, account updates and information about StarNow features, and messages from other StarNow members. 

You can easily unsubscribe from most of our emails, either by using the 'unsubscribe' link provided in the email, changing your email settings on your profile or by contacting us using the information provided below. Please note that you won't be able to unsubscribe from some emails relating to important activity on your account (e.g. payment receipts, message notifications) 

### Contact details

If you wish to contact us in relation to this privacy policy, our privacy standards, or our information-handling practices please contact us using the details below:

Email: [contact@starnow.com](mailto:contact@starnow.com)

Postal Address:  
StarNow Limited  
PO Box 6372, Marion Square  
Wellington, 6141  
New Zealand 

You may also contact our EU Representative directly, who will be happy to provide you with further assistance:

VeraSafe Ireland Ltd.  
Unit 3D North Point House North Point Business Park New Mallow Road  
Cork T23AT2P  
Ireland  
Phone: +1-617-398-7067  
Contact form: <https://www.verasafe.com/privacy-services/contact-article-27-representative>
